+65 93731871 jeffreydavid255@gmail.com github.com/Jeffrey-David linkedin.com/in/jeffrey-david-25a54a204 Portfolio: jeffrey-david.github.io

### **ABOUT**

Enthusiastic engineering graduate with a B.Tech in Computer Science from VIT, Vellore, bringing a solid foundation in technology and a proactive approach to problem-solving. Experienced in applying technical skills and industry knowledge gained at Accenture. Currently pursuing a Master's in Information Systems at NTU, with a commitment to continuous learning to keep up with the technological advancements.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Accenture Solutions Private Limited**

Bangalore, India

Advanced Application Engineering Analyst

2022/11 - 2023/08

- Trained in Apache Hadoop File System and learned to use different big data analytics tools like Apache Hive, Spark, Cassandra and more as a fresher.
- Designed, developed, and implemented end-to-end data pipelines using Hadoop ecosystem tools such as HDFS, Map-Reduce, Hive, and Pig.
- Successfully integrated data from various sources, enabling efficient processing and analysis within the Hadoop cluster.
- Documented processes, procedures, and best practices for Hadoop cluster management and data processing.

#### **INTERNSHIPS**

TalentKraft Pte Ltd

Singapore

AI Project Development Intern

2024/01 - Present

- Conduct research and data gathering on relevant data for goal setting and performance review.
- Design and Develop Gen AI based solution to assist organisations in their Goal Setting and 360 Performance Review Process

## The Sparks Foundation

Vellore, India

Graduate Rotational Internship Program (Remote)

2021/02 - 2021/03

- Conducted thorough data analysis to identify patterns, trends, and anomalies in diverse datasets.
- Evaluated the performance of machine learning models using appropriate metrics and fine-tuned algorithms for optimal results.
- Implemented data preprocessing techniques to clean, normalize, and transform raw data into suitable formats for machine learning models.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Nanyang Technological University

Singapore

Master of Science in Information Systems

2023/08 - Present

- CGPA: 4.80 / 5.00
- Completing in May, 2024
- Focusing on Data Science and Text Mining through my choice of coursework specialization.
- Courses: Text and Web Mining, Data Mining, Internet Programming, Research Methods for Data Analysis, Information Retrieval and Information Visualization

## **Vellore Institute of Technology**

Vellore, India

B.Tech Computer Science and Engineering

2018/06 - 2022/05

- CGPA: 8.78 / 10.00
- Core Courses: Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Database Management Systems, Computer Architecture
- Elective Courses: Web Mining, Statistical Data Analytics and Artificial Intelligence for Beginners

#### **SKILLS**

- Programming Python, Java, C, JavaScript
- Big Data Analytics Apache Hive, Apache Spark, Apache Hadoop
- Data Mining Machine Learning, Neural Networks, Natural Language Processing
- Data Visualization Tableau, D3.js
- Web Development HTML, CSS, Java Servlet, JSP, MySQL, AWS Deployment
- Soft Skills Self-Motivated, Detail-Oriented, Problem-Solving

### **PROJECTS**

# Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis of LGBTQ Issues in Singapore

Text Mining, Deep Learning, NLP, Tableau

2024/01 - Present

- Web Scrap data from online discussion platforms like Reddit and HardwareZone.
- Train and Evaluate a BERT based Transformer Model to for Sentiment and Aspect Classification
- Analyze the Aspect based Sentiments with respect to Time using Visualizations to gain insights.

## Twitter Sentiment Analysis with MLP, CNN and BERT

Text Mining, Deep Learning, NLP

2023/08 - 2023/11

- Developed a machine learning model using Multilayer Perceptron (MLP), Convolutional Neural Network (CNN), and BERT for Twitter Sentiment Analysis.
- Implemented data preprocessing, model training, and evaluation.
- Collaborated with team members to optimize model performance and accuracy.

# Singapore COVID-19 StoryBoard

Data Visualization, Tableau

2023/08 - 2023/11

- Developed a comprehensive COVID-19 StoryBoard focusing on the situation in Singapore.
- Utilized Tableau for creating insightful data visualizations and interactive dashboards.
- Collected and analyzed relevant data for the StoryBoard.

## **Elegancy Stay - Hotel Management System**

Web Development, AWS Deployment

2023/08 - 2023/11

- Developed a comprehensive Hotel Management System called "Elegancy Stay."
- Implemented features such as reservation management, room allocation, and billing.
- Collaborated with a team to ensure the successful completion of the project.

# Deep Learning Model for Analyzing Water Quality, Level, and Flow of Cauvery River

Deep Learning, Environmental Analysis

2021/11 - 2022/05

- Developed a Deep Learning model to analyze water quality, level, and flow of the Cauvery River in India.
- Implemented features to predict and monitor environmental parameters.
- Contributed to the understanding and assessment of water resources using advanced technology.

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certificate of Completion of Accenture Greenfield Training Program	2023/01 - 2022/11
• Intro to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning	2021/03 - 2021/04
Artificial Intelligence for Beginners	2020/04 - 2020/05
Machine Learning Using Python	2020/04 - 2020/05
<ul> <li>Statistical Data Analytics for Business Research</li> </ul>	2020/04 - 2020/05
Data Science for Engineers - NPTEL	2021/01 - 2021/03
Programming in Java	2016/05 - 2016/06